Evil is coming. Bring protection.
Scary Movie 5 is a comedy film directed by Malcolm D. Lee.
Home with their newly-formed family, happy parents Dan and Jody
are haunted by sinister, paranormal activities.
Determined to expel the insidious force, they install security cameras and
discover their family is being stalked by an evil dead demon.
Jody Sanders, played by Ashley French.
Dan Sanders, played by Simon Rex.
Charlie Sheen, played by Charlie Sheen.
Kathy, played by Gracie Whitton.
Lily, played by Ava Kolker.
Barbara, played by Heather Locklear.
Scary Movie 5 (stylized as Scary MoVie) is a 2013
American parody film directed by Malcolm D.
Lee, written by David Zucker and Pat Proft, and
produced by Zucker and Phil Dornfeld.
It is the standalone sequel to Scary Movie 4 (2006) and the
fifth installment in the Scary Movie film series.
It is the second and last film in the series to be distributed by The Weinstein
Company, as well as the only one not to involve Miramax Films.
The film stars Ashley Tisdale, Simon Rex, Erica Ash, Katrina
Bowden, Terry Crews, Heather Locklear, J.
Manoux, Mac Miller, Jerry O'Connell, Molly Shannon,
Snoop Dogg, Kate Walsh and Katt Williams.
The film is the only installment of the franchise not to feature Cindy
Campbell (played by Anna Faris) or Brenda Meeks (Regina Hall).
It premiered on April 11, at the Hollywood's ArcLight Cinerama Dome.
The film parodies various horror films and other popular culture.
Scary Movie 5 was released on April 12, 2013.
The film received negative reviews from critics and grossed $78.4 million,
making it the lowest-grossing film in the Scary Movie series.
A sequel, Scary Movie 6, is set for release in 2026,
with the Wayans brothers' involvement.
The film explores themes of ballet dancer, parody, sequel, spoof, horror spoof.
The tone is lighthearted.